Contact

sthrnwmn@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/donnamccauley-rn-msn-ccrnccns-066236178 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare
Hospitals
Critical Care Nursing

Donna McCauley RN,MSN,CCRN,CCNS

Associate Manager, Clinical Services at Edwards Lifesciences Greenville, South Carolina Area

Summary

Experienced Care Specialist with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Public Speaking, Critical Care Nursing, Healthcare Management, Healthcare, and Leadership. Strong healthcare services professional with a MSN focused in Clinical Specialist Critical Care from California State University-Long Beach.

Experience

Edwards Lifesciences
Associate Manager, Clinical Services Critical Care at Edwards
Lifesciences
December 2019 - Present (8 months)
East Coast

Prisma Health
Critical Care Clinical Practice Specialist
December 2018 - December 2019 (1 year 1 month)
Greenville, South Carolina Area

The RN Clinical Practice Specialist (RN CPS) is

- an advanced practitioner who functions as an expert clinician in a particular specialty of nursing practice.
- an expert in evidence-based nursing & practice; conscious professionalism and inter-professional collaboration.
- a leader & change agent to achieve quality cost-effective, evidence-based outcomes.
- responsible for designing, implementing & evaluating patient-specific & population-based programs of care.

- responsible for providing consultation to other nursing & health professional staff in an area of specialization.
- responsible for empowerment of the direct care nurse through education.
- serves as expert consultant on complex patients & collaborating with the clinical nurse to develop plans of care

Bon Secours St Francis Med Ctr Critical Clinical Nurse Specialist April 2017 - December 2018 (1 year 9 months)

Greenville, South Carolina Area

Served in the role as Critical Care Clinical Specialist for General Intensive Care Unit, Cardiac Intensive Care Unit as well as Open Heart Unit. Served in the role of expert practitioner, leader, educator, advocate as well as primary role of the integration of current evidence into daily practice.

In addition to the traditional roles and expectations of the CNS position, within the past year, served as Clinical Lead for the Critical Care Progressive Mobility program which was put into place in collaboration with Physical Therapy to promote better clinical outcomes for our patients. Also, served as lead and coordinator for integration of the most current hemodynamic monitoring technology into the evaluation and care of our critically ill with more focus on evaluating hemodynamic parameters that assist with diagnosing and managing our critically ill with the goal to more rapidly assess, diagnosis and treat those patient most at risk (Edwards Hemosphere and EV1000 technology). I serve as the administrator for our Glucostabilizer software program to facilitate the most current EVP for DKA as well as HHS and hyperglycemia. Provided Critical Care Education and integration for 18 RN new graduates into the Critical Care Units as well as several Med-Surg transfers. Develop EVP protocols and integrate them into daily practice. Consult on many of our critically ill to discuss treatment modality, response to therapy, possible additional treatment options/support. Worked with vendors to obtain quotes for new equipment/technology for the upcoming fiscal year. Serves as consult for the new Intermediate Care Unit for setting up inclusion/ exclusion and transfer criteria as well as patient management concepts and education plan.

Abiomed
Regional Clinical Manager Southeast
November 2014 - February 2017 (2 years 4 months)
Southeast Region

Role included overseeing the clinical education and support provided by the Clinical Educators and Clinical Consultants within the southeastern region of the US. Provided direction education regarding the cardiac patient requiring device support to physicians, mid-levels, critical care staff as well as cath lab team. Also involved in the daily management of these patient types for optimizing hemodynamics and best outcome opportunities.

Clemson University
Adjunct Clinical Instructor Critical Care
January 2001 - November 2014 (13 years 11 months)
Clemson SC

Bon Secours St Francis Med Ctr Critical Care Clinical Nurse Specialist January 2000 - November 2014 (14 years 11 months) Greenville, South Carolina Area

Education

California State University-Long Beach MSN, Clinical Specialist Critical Care · (1993 - 1995)

The University of Tennessee at Knoxville BSN, Nursing · (1979 - 1983)